# Siddaiah M

A Senior Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in full-stack web and mobile app development, project management, and JavaScript. Excellent problem-solving skills and ability to work collaboratively in fast-paced environments. Dedicated to continuously learning and adopting new technologies to drive innovation.

### Bengaluru, India

**4** +91 98800 97556

siddayya96@gmail.com

inkedin.com/in/siddaiahm

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Software Engineer at Orxa Energies, Bengaluru

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT

- → I led the design, development, and deployment of an ERP tool for internal procurement management, using the MERN stack. This project involved creating robust solutions to streamline procurement processes, enhance efficiency, and improve overall business operations. My role included architecting scalable systems, ensuring seamless integration across modules, and optimizing performance to meet the company's specific requirements.
- → Modernized the company's UI, boosting its appeal with animations and enhancing SEO using Next.js and React, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement and a 15% improvement in SEO.
- → Designed and Developed a mobile application using React Native that interacts with a bike dashboard cluster. The app tracks bike trip history, provides map navigation, offers ride analytics, and includes a forum for rider interaction. Built the backend infrastructure for the same features using Node.js, Express, and MongoDB, ensuring seamless integration with REST APIs and WebSockets.
- → Designed and developed a bike dashboard cluster using Node.js, React, and Electron, which interacts with a bike ESP32 via UART to display real-time bike data, map navigation, settings and customizable themes. Implemented a custom OS to automatically run this dashboard application at startup using Linux and Raspberry Pi (RPI), enhancing user experience and system functionality.

## Software Development Engineer at MountBlue Technologies, Bengaluru

FEB 2020 - JULY 2021

- → Created custom components to facilitate code reuse and reduce the overall size of the application.
- → Implemented automated testing with Jest and Enzyme to ensure code quality and reduce the number of bugs in production.
- → Developed a real-time chat feature for the application using WebSockets.
- → Collaborated with other developers to ensure code consistency and ensure adherence to best practices.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, HTML, CSS,
ReactJs, React Native, Expo,
Redux, Redux Thunk,
NodeJs, ExpressJs, Redis,
MongoDB, Mongoose,
MySQL, Sequelize, PostgreSQL,
Git, Bitbucket, Jira,
NextJs, ElectronJs,
AntDesign, Material UI, Tailwind,
AWS, EC2, S3, Firebase,
Front End Web Development,
Responsive Web Development,
Debugging, Problem-Solving

#### **EDUCATION**

B.Tech, Computer Science and Engineering, Bangalore

AUGUST 2016 - MAY 2020 CGPA - 7.74

#### **PROJECTS**

#### SOU-BUDE ( Android / iOS )

- Bike sharing app includes map navigation, ride history, wallet and role based controls.

#### Indeanta ( Android / iOS )

- This app provides In-Campus "ALL ELECTRIC" mobility solutions, this includes wallet, scan and pay ride charges, has a map that shows vehicles movement and availability, offers and coupons.